Hey my name is Addison from Captain Bills and I'm going to tell you how to buy an outdoor volleyball net.
If you are very serious about playing outdoor volleyball you would want to get a very durable net.
One that will last you awhile, those you cannot find in any sporting good stores.
You are going to have to go online, a lot of places in Florida or in California have very durable nets, outdoor volleyball nets that can be used on a day to day basis.
If you are not serious and just use it for recreational use you can find one a pretty decent one at a sporting good store.
It may not last you as long but if you are not using it everyday it would be a perfect fit for just the recreational use.
So when going to a sporting good store a lot of times you'll find there's badminton and volleyball packages and there are combination packages.
Those may not be regulation, so one thing you can do is look online and if under the volleyball net that you are looking for it says AVP quality or AVP certified.
AVP is the association of volleyball professionals.
So that is what the professional volleyball players use.
So if you find a net that says AVP quality or AVP certified that's going to be the most durable net to use when playing outdoor volleyball.
Another thing you need to look for is who you are buying it for. If you are buying it for men's, you are going to need to have a certain height for the net.
The men's height is seven feet eleven inches.
And the women's height is seven feet four inches.
Women's height can also be used for juniors or kids.
Also the width and the length of the volleyball court is thirty feet by sixty feet so you want to make sure that you get lines that fulfill those requirements for the volleyball net.
Volleyball lines and that is how to buy a volleyball net.